Okay, so, I just hit 30
days of daily vlogging. 30 days,
one video every single day, no
exceptions. And, honestly, I
almost quit three separate times.
But I learned three things that
completely changed how I make
videos. And, I want to walk
you through all three of them
right now. So lesson number one
is that, editing is where videos
actually get made. I used to
think the shoot was the hard
part. It's not.
my first vlogs took me 45
minutes to shoot then, like, four
hours to edit. Four hours. The
thing that saved me was, cutting
silence automatically instead of
scrubbing the timeline by hand
looking for dead air. Once I
stopped doing that manually, my
edit time dropped by more than
half. And that brings me to
lesson two, and this is the
one that blew my mind. Nobody
watches your intro, nobody. I
looked at my retention graphs and
80 % of people were gone
before minute one. So I started
cutting my videos to open on
the single most interesting
sentence I said that day. No
hello, no welcome back. Just
straight into the point. And my
average view duration doubled,
doubled. In one week, that one
change did more than everything
else I tried in the entire
month combined. Let me, give you
a concrete example of that. Last
Tuesday I filmed a video about
my morning routine and the best
moment was, me spilling coffee on
my desk at minute six. The
old me would have opened with,
like, a whole explanation of what
morning routines are. Instead I
opened on the spill and, the
retention line just stayed flat
the entire video. retention is
basically the holy grail, if you
didn't know. Lesson three is,
quieter, but it might be the
most important one. Consistency
beats quality. Not because quality
doesn't matter, but because, you
only get good by shipping. My
day one video is, like,
embarrassing. My day 30 video is
something I'm actually proud of.
And there is no version of
this where I skip the embarrassing
ones and jump straight to the
good ones. So, that's the whole
month. Cut the dead air, kill
your intro, and ship every single
day. you want to see the
before and after retention graphs,
I put them in a follow
-up video, so subscribe so you
don't miss it. And I will
see you tomorrow.